<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on 🎨 Blog de @carlogilmar</title><link>https://carlogilmar.xyz/categories/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on 🎨 Blog de @carlogilmar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://carlogilmar.xyz/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Phoenix Live Views</title><link>https://carlogilmar.xyz/posts/live_views/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlogilmar.xyz/posts/live_views/</guid><description>The content below was generated for prepare a talk for the Elixir Meetup in CDMX 🇲🇽
All the drawings were drew my me.
The Phoenix Live Views is an open-source project created since last October, 2018. The core maintainers are Chris McCord, Jose Valim, Alex Garibay, Gary Rennie and Scott Newcomer. Join to the Elixir Community Slack!
In the next sections I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what is and how I understood that this works 😅.</description></item><item><title>Learning IoT: First Steps with Elixir</title><link>https://carlogilmar.xyz/posts/learning-iot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlogilmar.xyz/posts/learning-iot/</guid><description>Recently I have the opportunity to give a conference in the Startup Week in Mexico City. So I decided talk about Internet of things, because I was learning this using an Arduino and a Raspberry Pi.
DEMO Connect Everything! The project is create a simple web application for create distribuid music. I was inspired in the Launchpad App and the Smartphone Symphony.
I planned make this using Phoenix Framework, and connect an Arduino for play the music.</description></item><item><title>Learning Swift</title><link>https://carlogilmar.xyz/posts/learning-swift/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlogilmar.xyz/posts/learning-swift/</guid><description>Learning Swift Recently I have been studying about Swift. I think that the learning experience is a wonderful resource for other persons who are in the same situation, so I consider valuable talk about this. First Steps When I start to learn swift I decide to watch videos and demonstrations about how to use the Xcode for build iOS apps, but, for be honest, I couldn’t understand some things: optionals, constrains, auto layout… This was my first experience.</description></item><item><title>Learning Ember JS</title><link>https://carlogilmar.xyz/posts/learning-ember/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlogilmar.xyz/posts/learning-ember/</guid><description>Follow with learning more about Ember Js as our JS framework, I have to talk about my learning experience.
When I was searching about Ember I found a lot of resources: posts, books, videos, courses and more. Everything looks good, until I had to start my first projects.
Before to start I think that is good to know the context about it. Ember JS was born as a fork from SproutCore Framework.</description></item><item><title>Process in Elixir: A Simple Example</title><link>https://carlogilmar.xyz/posts/elixir-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlogilmar.xyz/posts/elixir-process/</guid><description>In the last days I have been learning about Process in Elixir. After doing some exercises and understand some things about it, I can explain how to create a simple example about process.
The Process Work with process in Elixir is so common, so, it’s important know how to use it. For create a process you can use spawn (which takes a function).
The process structure is very simple: you have a mailbox, created within a function and by the word receive, and you can manage different messages and do something.</description></item></channel></rss>